Andy Rubin，2013年带领Google's Android团队，
Andy Rubin, head of Google's Android team in 2013,
在Twitter上发布Android's开放性这个著名定义，
famously defined Android's openness with this Tweet, offering the
并提供下载和构建Android的源代码和指令。
instructions for downloading and building the Android source code.
作为开发人员，这让我们很容易就看到幕后，
As app developers, it's handy to be able to peep
看到这个框架是如何工作的。
behind the curtains and see how the framework actually
而堆栈溢出则是找到答案的最佳途径。
works. And it's an excellent way to find answers to
但是对于Android开源项目，
tricky, Stack Overflow questions. But the Android Open Source
或者称为AOSP，它的功能远不止如此。
Project, or AOSP as its commonly known, is much more
源代码是在Apache 2 协议下可用的，
than that. The source code is available under the
所以任何人都可以开发它来实现做想做的事，
Apache 2 license, so anyone can take it and do
包括在原有基础上修改和重构。
anything they want with it, including modifying it and redistributing
Android一直都有由modders组成的充满激情的社区，
it. And they have. Android has always had a passionate
Steve Kondik 和 Cyanogen 以及社会各界的XDA，
community of modders, from Steve Kondik and the Cyanogen community
还有其他开发人员，一直在尝试、开发、发布，
to XDA and many others who have been distributing modified
关于 Android手机端的图片修改。
images of Android for phone owners brave enough to try
甚至在像亚马逊这样的大公司，都在用Android的源代码，
them. Even big companies like Amazon have taken the Android
进行修改后投入自己的产品线使用。
source code and modified it for use in their own
这种开放性的扩展已经体现到应用程序本身，
line of products. That openness extends to the apps themselves, the
AOSP包括拨号程序、程序启动器、
AOSP includes key mobile apps like the dialer, app launcher,
日历、邮件这类的核心应用程序。Google还为他们提供自己的版本。
calendar, and email. And Google offers it own versions of each
在早期，程序与本地框架紧密结合，
as well. In the early days those native apps were
只能在该平台更新。
tightly bound to the framework and could only get updated along
无可否认，这是在初期，大概每隔几个星期更新一次。
with the platform. Which admittedly in the early days seemed like
但是这个时间对于平台间的发行来说过长了，
every few weeks. But as the time between platform releases grew,
所以将程序与平台解绑，而是通过
so did the efforts to unbundle those apps, allowing
Google Play来发布更新。
them to be updated through Google Play. That was great
这对用户来说，无疑是个好消息，
news for users, but it had an even better
但是在开发人员看来却不是这样。
side effect for us developers. Because apps like Gmail and
因为像Gmail和Maps这些应用程序依赖于一些谷歌专有的API，
Maps depend on a number of proprietary Google APIs,
Google发布了Google Play服务。同时也以餐前点心命名，
Google released Google Play Services. Also code named after food
用来支持Google应用程序，并且向开发人员开放API，
to support the Google apps, while also giving us
像Maps, Wallet, Drive 和 YouTube。
developers Google specific APIs, like Maps, Wallet, Drive, and YouTube.
所以现在我们会在每周六左右得到最新最好的Google特有的API。
So now we get the latest and greatest Google specific APIs
而不是依赖于特定的平台，
every six weeks or so. And rather than being tied to
它们可以在任意设备上使用，可以去了解一下android 2.3。
a specific platform, they're available on every device, back to Gingerbread.
哦，当然，每一个原生应用程序也都可以替换。
Oh, and of course every native app is also entirely replaceable.
所以你可以发布一些应用程序来取代设备自带的。
So you can publish apps to replace any of the apps
我们也可以创建自己的SMS apps、
shipped with the device. And we can build our own SMS
homescreens 和 maps apps，将它们公开在平台上，
apps, homescreens or maps apps, publish it on Play and give
让用户自己选择使用。
users the choice to make it their default. When Android was first
在Android第一次发布的时候，Andy Rubin是这样描述AOSP的，
announced, Andy Rubin described the AOSP as, all the software
所以运行在手机上的软件没有没遇到过阻碍的，
to run a mobile phone but without the proprietary obstacles
但从不会有能阻碍移动创新。
that have hindered mobile innovation. Today, Android runs on more
现在，有不同的版本在移动端工作，但是它们的核心都是相同的。
than just mobiles, but the core of its purpose remains
在一个平台系统上，允许模型、运营商、
the same. A platform and ecosystem that allows models, carriers,
原始设备制造商以及应用程序开发人员一起创新和竞争。
OEMs and app developers to innovate and compete. So, armed
所以，应当开放、不断发展和增长的Google API平台，
with an open, evolving platform enriched by a growing set
同时提供功能丰富的应用程序，
of Google API's and the ability to create great apps
让用户能够自己定制自己的用户体验，
that let users customize every aspect of
你还能使用他人的工作成果，
their user experience, you can use other people's
来开发确定以后的开放平台。
work to help define the computing platform of
这就是我对开放的定义。
the future. And that's my definition of open.